

CONTACT

@ codes.mariam@gmail.com

www.mariam.pro

github.com/mavima

in linkedin.com/in/maria-vihla-manninen

TOP SKILLS

Ruby | Ruby on Rails

HTML | CSS | SCSS

JavaScript | JQuery | React

PHP | WordPress | Figma

SQL | Git | SEO

Project Management

LANGUAGES

English - Full working proficiency

Finnish - Full working proficiency

French - Working proficiency

Spanish - Working proficiency

German - Limited working proficiency

PERSONAL WEB PROJECTS

recipeper.com - bilingual RoR application for storing and sharing recipes and links.

famtravel.eu - community for travelling families.

MARIA MANNINEN

WEB DEVELOPER

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Originally a journalist, I have also worked in administration in international environment.

Since 2019 I have concentrated in web development, both back-end and front-end.

Finding solutions and creating beautiful design is my goal and pleasure.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Backend Software Engineer atHome Group S.à r.l., 11/2022 - present

Freelance Web Developer

Independent, 9/2019 - 11/2022

- Creating websites for clients, often using Wordpress and other CMS platforms, PHP.
- Developing applications for personal projects using Ruby on Rails and React.

Business Support Officer

Nordea Investment Funds S.A., 9/2015 - 4/2019

- Expense follow-up and reporting.
- Event organisation and assistance of the management.

Assistant of the Ambassador

Embassy of Finland in Luxembourg, 5/2013 – 8/2015

Schedule Editor

Rovi Corporation S.A., 11/2012 - 5/2013

News Reporter, Editor, News Reader

Several medias in Finland, 2003 - 2007

EDUCATION

Master of Arts (literature, communications, languages)

University of Turku, Finland 2003

Full Stack Ruby on Rails Bootcamp

Le Wagon Barcelona 2019